Bret Petersen

UX Designer, Interactive Art Director, and Animator

Minneapolis, MN 55404 (willing to relocate) • 415.939.1779 • <u>bretpetersen@gmail.com</u> <u>bretpetersen.com</u> • <u>linkedin.com/in/bret-petersen</u> • <u>github.com/bretpeters3n</u>

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

UX Designer, Interactive Art Director, and Animator with development experience who enjoys the fast-paced environment of the digital industry and being part of pioneering teams. Motion designer who enjoys creating interaction and animation filled mobile and desktop experiences.

Core Competencies and Skills: Adobe Animate, Tumult Hype, Unity, GSAP, Google Web Designer, Figma, Sketch, Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, and Flash.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front End Web Developer and Designer • Coolibar, St. Louis Park, MN

02/2022 - current

- Updated website with new company logo and redesigned site navigation.
- Increased accessibility of e-commerce store by conforming to current web standards. Key achievement: Introduced use of video for collection releases.

UX/UI Designer • Irish Titan, St. Louis Park, MN

03/2020 - 06/2021

- Communicated with clients to discover their needs and fine tune their projects.
- Researched and tested e-commerce apps for use on our client's online stores.

Key achievement: Expedited adoption of Figma as the main software design tool.

Web Specialist • United Healthcare, Hopkins, MN

08/2019 - 12/2019

- Animated advertisements and designed emails.
- Helped usher in more efficient email coding with the use of templates.

Key achievement: Received 'Employee of the Month' honor.

Web Animator • Target, Minneapolis, MN

07/2018 - 02/2019

- Created animated advertisements while working alongside a team of designers and developers.
- Introduced 3D animation into advertisements to increase their noticeability.

Key achievement: Facilitated faster workflow using Hype as main animation software.

Lead Web Designer & Web Animator • San Francisco, CA

10/2004 - 04/2018

Worked at Organic Inc, AKQA, among other agencies while working my way up to Lead Designer.

- Participated in conceptual brainstorming, designed out concepts, and animated ads based on concepts.
- Responsible for designing websites, creating style guides, working within brand guidelines.

EDUCATION

VR: Intro to Unity, World Building, and App Dev Certificates • Universe (online)	2022 - current
Full Stack Web Development Certificate • University of Minnesota (online)	2021
UX Certificate • Brainco (Minneapolis, MN)	2019
Bachelor of Fine Arts in Graphic Design • University of Minnesota Duluth	2000-2004

Cum Laude & Departmental Honors